人人影視
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
字幕組招新中
请访问 YYSubs.com
翻譯   辰星曉Reginamoon   -小y   吃冰棒
《失落的祕符》前情提要
Previously on "The Lost Symbol"...
這是一個重大突破
This is breakthrough stuff.
而且我們也許只發現了冰山一角
And we may only be scratching the surface.
翻譯    哈里不是波特   司柏   易碎的絕對
扎克里·所羅門死於土耳其的監獄暴動
Zachary Solomon died in a prison riot in Turkey.
機密信息
-我們需要蘭登  -那彼得·所羅門呢
- We need Langdon. - What about Peter Solomon?
翻譯    DerbyNinja   Caroline   冰島豆腐
彼得在天堂和地獄之間的分界線
Peter is in the borderland between Heaven and Hell.
他可能已經死了
He might already be dead.
-這只是塊石頭  -這是一幅地圖
- It's a piece of rock. - It's a map!
校對    蘇葵
金字塔和尖頂石會揭示出入口的位置
The pyramid and the capstone will reveal the location of the portal.
希伯來文...是密碼
The Hebrew... it's code.
時間軸    Caroline   愛說謊的孩子
那枚戒指可能包含某種解密祕鑰
The ring could contain some kind of decryption.
我在照你的意思做
I am doing what you wanted.
後期    MythCreator
我叫你單獨行動
You were told to do it alone.
甩掉她
Cut her loose.
總監    蘇葵
你不能待在這裏
Hey, you can't be in here, man.
公園關門了
Park's closed.
身份證拿出來
Let's see some ID.
醫生說他的搭檔應該能痊癒
The doctors say his partner should make a full recovery.
那他呢
What about him?
現在下定論爲時尚早
Too early to say.
我曾被派往七千英里之外去打極端主義者
I got sent 7,000 miles away to fight extremists.
這不是你的戰爭
This isn't your fight.
我身上的彈孔可不是這麼說的
I got a hole in my side that says otherwise.
昨天有件證物失蹤了
Some evidence went missing yesterday.
彼得·所羅門的戒指
Peter Solomon's ring.
你不會恰好知情吧
You happen to know anything about that?
你在說什麼
What are you saying?
我是說  如果...
I'm saying if--
假設...
hypothetically--
你在幫蘭登和凱瑟琳
you were aiding Langdon and Katherine,
那你這麼做只會將他們置於險境
you'd only be putting them in more danger.
你無法從做了這些事的人手中保護他們
You can't protect them from the guy who did this.
你沒必要擔心我
You don't have to worry about me.
我已經逞夠英雄了
I'm done playing the hero.
我向我妻子承諾過
Made my wife a promise.
你最好能遵守諾言
Make sure you keep it.
甜蜜的家
Home sweet home.
你做了炸香蕉嗎  親愛的
Oh, you make tostones, babe?
別抱太大希望
I wouldn't get my hopes up.
什麼
What?
歡迎回家
Welcome home.
-你好呀  -感覺如何
- Hey. - How you feeling?
餓死了
Hungry.
我是說過你們可以待在這裏破譯聖經密碼
I said you guys could set up here, to crack your Bible code,
沒說把我的食物都吃光
not eat all my food.
我就不打擾你和你的新朋友們了
I'll leave you to your new friends.
-也許我們該走了  -別啊  她沒事
- Maybe we should go. - No. She's fine.
她只是擔心我
She's just worried about me.
再說了  我覺得現在別出去比較好
Besides, I wouldn't go anywhere right now.
我們有個尾巴
We got a lurker.
隔壁第三棟  北面
Three houses down, north side.
-他找到我們了  -不  那是佐藤的人
- He's found us. - No, it's Sato's people.
她去醫院找過你們倆
She came to the hospital looking for you two.
如果你猜錯了  那是邁拉克
And if you're wrong and it's Mal'akh
或是他派來的人  那怎麼辦
or someone he sent, what then?
他爲何要那樣做  他需要你
Why would he do that? He needs you.
你怎麼了
What's going on with you?
沒有  沒事  我沒事
Nothing. Nothing, I'm fine.
別糊弄我  羅伯特
Don't bullshit me, Robert.
有些事我沒告訴你
There's something I haven't told you.
我們在圖書館時  他打來了電話
He called when we were at the library.
誰
Who?
邁拉克
Mal'akh.
他說得很清楚
And he made it very clear
他想讓我單獨行動
that he wants me doing this on my own.
不能帶你
Without you.
-你之前沒告訴我  -我不想嚇到你
- And you didn't tell me this before? - I didn't want to scare you.
是嗎  還是你也贊同他的想法
Right. Or maybe you agree with him.
也許你覺得單獨行動會更好
Maybe you think you'd be better off doing this alone.
-這不是贊同與否的問題  -我爸在他手上
- It's not about agreeing with him. - He has my father.
而是承認他所呈現的一切
It's about acknowledging the very
-非常危險  -我哪裏也不去
- real danger he presents. - I'm not going anywhere.
他有真正的殺手...
He has a literal assassin...
你覺得這就能讓我停手
And that's what it's going to take to get me to stop.
失落的祕符
第一季第三集
貝拉米先生  埃裏森·布萊克  中情局
Mr. Bellamy, Ellison Blake, Central Intelligence.
抱歉讓你久等了
Sorry to keep you waiting.
我可不信
Oh, I doubt that.
看來你一點沒浪費時間
Looks like you put your time here to good use.
抓緊時間看書
Caught up on a little reading.
我懷念書
Uh, I miss books.
科幻小說  曾是我的初戀
Sci-fi-- that was my first love.
我知道這不是高雅讀物
I know it's not high art,
但這股吸引
but the stakes--
還有什麼比世界末日的故事更刺激精彩
I mean, how can you beat a story about the end of the world?
現在我沒什麼時間看書了
I don't get much time to read anymore.
不看小說了
Not fiction.
不過沒關係  因爲我發現
But that's okay, because I've come to realize
最有趣的故事...
that the most interesting stories...
是真實存在的
...are true.
我不知道這是什麼
I don't know what that is.
我知道
I do.
這是利維坦社的符號
That's the sign for the Leviathan Group.
這是共濟會的一個祕密組織
It's a secret sect within the Freemasons,
你所屬的組織
to which you belong.
我還知道  他們的目的是爲了保護
I also know that their purpose is to protect
一些非常古老  非常有價值的信息
some very old, very valuable information.
所以我想問你
So my question for you is:
它在哪
where is it?
傳說中的入口在哪
This portal that I've heard about.
我不知道你在說什麼
I don't know what you're talking about.
但我知道你不能把我關在這
But I do know that you can't keep me here.
確實
No.
不是關在這
Not here.
有蘭登的消息嗎
Any word on Langdon?
還沒有  我派人去找他了
Not yet. Got people looking.
-那他呢  -他口風很嚴
- What about him? - Mm, he's the quiet type.
我覺得他需要換個環境
I think he could use a change of scenery.
把他送去索斯伍德
Have him moved over to Southwoods.
巴比倫語
埃及語
希臘語
波斯語
時鐘靠近
水域
碼頭
動物園
好了  到哪一步了
All right, where are we?
對  這是個方程  有可能是方程
Okay, it's an equation. Maybe an equation.
有可能是...或者是座標
Maybe a... Or coordinates?
希伯來字母
《創世紀》第一章第一節
有可能是座標
Maybe coordinates.
14個字母
不是
No.
還有什麼
So what else?
密鑰...  希爾密碼
Ciphers... A Hill cipher.
有可能是希爾密碼
Maybe a Hill cipher.
答案就在眼前  答案就在眼前
It's right here. It's right here.
該死的
Damn it.
-又繞回到變位詞上了  -還是完全沒有頭緒
- Back to anagrams? - Back to nowhere.
很明顯  這段希伯來文按照某種密鑰篡改了
Clearly, a cipher was used to alter the Hebrew,
某種帶着
likely one with...
共濟會特徵或主題的密碼
Masonic characteristics or themes.
我怎麼也破解不了
I-I j... I just cannot figure out what it is.
或許跟所羅門的故事有關
Well, maybe it's related to the Solomon story.
爸跟我說起共濟會時
When Dad talked about the Masons,
總說那是一種美好的道德體系
he always said it was a beautiful system of morality
-隱藏於寓言之中  -隱藏於寓言之中  對
- veiled in allegory. - Veiled in allegory, yes.
它就在我們的眼皮底下
It's in there, hiding in plain sight.
我應該可以看出來  但我...無法思考
I should be able to see it, but I... can't think.
我卡住了
I'm blocked.
你還是再考慮一下吧
Please reconsider.
-不  -我的大腦  它...
- No. - My-my brain, it...
如果你總是讓我擔驚受怕  它沒法工作
it can't work if I'm constantly worried about you.
謝謝你這麼關心我  但我不會讓這個人
Well, that's very sweet, but I'm not gonna let this guy
說我不能參與解救我父親的行動
tell me that I can't participate in saving my own dad's life.
但是  如果我破解不了密碼  我們就救不了他
But... we're not gonna save him if I can't work this out.
-我們會想出辦法的  蘭登  -凱瑟琳...
- We are going to work this out, Langdon. - Katherine...
總有一天你會意識到
At some point, you are going to realize
其實你需要我  知道嗎
that you actually need me, you know that?
你對很多領域都涉獵頗深
You have vast knowledge in-in many topics.
但破解密碼的確不是你的強項
Codebreaking isn't one of them.
重要的是這不是我的領域  而是你的
It's not my knowledge that's important, it's yours.
破解密碼的鑰匙就埋在你意識的深處
The key to decoding this is buried in your mind...
我知道怎麼把它挖出來
and I know how to dig it out.
他在變虛弱
He's getting weaker.
但我們不能操之過急
But we can't rush the process.
你比誰都清楚這點
You know that better than anyone.
這是他兒子的東西
This things belonged to his boy.
他們會在阿拉弗找到他
They will find him in the Araf.
到那時  他就能看清自己的真面目了
Then he will see himself for who he truly is.
你心中最大的期盼是什麼
What is the predominant wish of your heart?
他女兒有下落了嗎
Has his daughter surfaced?
沒有  目前爲止  她還是不知所蹤
No. She's still off the grid, as far as I can tell.
如果他們無視我的警告
If they've ignored my warning...
那就只能給他們一點顏色看看了
...then they must be made to understand.
已到達
華盛頓東北區紐頓街24號
好吧
Okay.
早日康復
翠茜
Trish.
多謝關心  你還給我帶了奶油煎餅卷
Aw, that's so sweet. You got me cannolis?
還是我最愛的果醬
That's my jam.
好吧
Okay.
還抱上了
We're hugging.
快進來  你買了新電動車
Come on inside. Did you get a new EV?
真好看  開了多少公里了
That looks great. How many miles are you getting?
-什麼  -是啊
- What? - Yeah.
稍等
Hang tight.
好吧
Okay.
非常感謝你能來
Thank you so much for coming.
那是誰
So, who was that?
爲什麼要我偷偷摸摸地把你實驗室設備
And why am I sneaking you lab equipment
-放在糕點盒裏帶來  -晚點跟你解釋
- disguised as baked goods? - I'll explain later.
你是在開玩笑  對嗎
You're kidding, right?
聽着  我知道這話有點故弄玄虛
Listen, I know how this is gonna sound,
但你知道得越少越好
but the less you know the better.
你沒事吧
Is everything okay?
都挺好的  我保證
Everything's fine. I promise.
我只是很趕時間
Um, I'm just really pressed for time,
但你這麼大老遠過來幫我  真的感激不盡
but I can't thank you enough for coming all the way out here.
我明天聯繫你
And I'll call you tomorrow.
反正你是老闆
It's your name on the door.
幫我個忙
Hey, do me a favor?
替我向剛剛抱過我的那個陌生人道個別
Say goodbye to the complete stranger that just hugged me?
太酷了
That's tight.
這玩意兒到底是幹什麼的
So what's this thing do, anyway?
讓凱瑟琳對不喜歡我的部分重新進行設定
It lets Katherine reprogram the parts in me she doesn't like.
不  那需要更多的設備才行
Oh, no, that requires much more equipment.
你這輩子已經掌握那麼多關於密碼的數據
With all the cryptographic data you've absorbed over your life,
問題不是你有沒有答案
it's not a question of having the answer.
我們知道答案就在裏面
We know it's in there.
只是有太多別的噪音干擾
There's just too much other noise.
通過可以提升神經活動的聽覺刺激
With auditory stimuli that can boost neurological activity,
我們可以顯示出你做出反應的頻率
we can elicit your frequency following response,
把噪音屏蔽掉  從而找出答案
drown out that noise and find it.
最好是能有個封閉的環境
It would be best if we had a closed environment.
明白了  我這就走  你們自便
Ah, yeah. Sure, I'll leave y'all to it.
躺回去  放鬆
Lie back. Relax.
我們的能量相互連接會有助於你放鬆
Interconnecting our energies will help you relax.
傾聽節奏
Listen to the beats,
傾聽我的聲音
to the sound of my voice.
慢慢地吸氣
Inhale slowly.
很好  然後呼氣
Good. And exhale.
把注意力放到腳上
Concentrate on your feet.
它們很溫暖...
They're warm...
沉重
heavy.
讓那種溫暖向上在你身體中流動
Let that warmth flow up through your body.
隨着暖意的流動...
And as it does...
感受你的身體也越來越沉重
feel your body growing heavy as well.
隨着你感受到身體越來越沉重
And as you feel your body become heavier
越來越溫暖
and warmer,
感受你自己沉入了地面...
feel yourself sinking into the floor...
被下面的溫暖所包裹...
...being enveloped by the warmth beneath...
轉移到了一個新的地方...
...being delivered to a new place...
那是貯存你所有的知識和經驗的地方
where all of your knowledge and experience reside.
是誰請求進入
Who asks for admission here?
一個身處黑暗之中的可憐之人
A poor candidate in a state of darkness.
你心中最大的期盼是什麼
What is the predominant wish of your heart?
看到光明
To see the light.
扎克里
Zachary?
我莊嚴地保證並宣誓
I solemnly promise and swear
我絕不會暴露
that I will never reveal the secret arts
屬於共濟會的
and hidden mysteries belonging
保密藝術和隱藏祕密
to Free and Accepted Masons.
如果我故意違背這個誓言
Should I knowingly violate this oath,
我自願接受懲罰  接受被割喉
I expect no less penalty than to have my throat cut across,
舌頭被從根拔出
my tongue torn out by its roots
-不  -我的身體被埋在...
- No. - and my body buried in the rough...
不
No!
爸爸...
Dad...
祕密就是怎樣死
The secret is how to die.
信號閥值
把涌現出來的字告訴我
Tell me the words as they come to you.
所羅門
Solomon.
護身符
Amulet.
戒指
Ring.
列王
Kings.
智慧
Wise.
心
Heart.
你感覺如何
How do you feel?
還行
Fine.
你沒讓我做丟臉的事吧
You didn't make me do anything embarrassing, like...
比如學狗叫  或...
bark like a dog or...
說唱吧
rap?
差不多吧
Close.
所羅門
護身符
戒指
列王
智慧
心
僕人
判斷
劍
智慧
心
僕人
"我就應允你所求的  賜你聰明智慧"
"Lo, I have given thee a wise and understanding heart."
我要看看《聖經》
I-I need to see a Bible.
小心點
Careful.
打擾一下
Excuse me.
你能不能幫我看一會東西
Would you mind watching my stuff for a moment?
-我要...  -沒問題
- I have to... - Yeah, no problem.
-除非你準備走了  -沒事
- Unless you're about to leave. - No, it's fine.
我會在這裏待一會
I'm gonna be here for a while.
正希望你這麼說
I was hoping you'd say that.
-謝謝  -沒事
- Thank you. - Sure.
篡改《聖經》文本的人替換了一些詞
Whoever altered the Bible text replaced some of the words.
在《列王紀上》中
In First Kings,
上帝將聰明智慧賜予所羅門
God gave Solomon a wise and understanding heart,
讓他成爲神話中的傳奇統治者
making him the legendary ruler of myth.
但是這裏的文本被人篡改了
But here that script was changed.
不再是"聰明智慧"
It no longer reads "Wise and understanding heart."
而只是"睿智"
It just reads "Wisdom."
這對於幫你破譯信息有用嗎
So that's supposed to help you unscramble the letters?
這就是所謂的關鍵詞密鑰
It's what's known as a keyword cipher.
就像這樣  你們看
It works like this. Here.
你把"睿智"兩個詞的字母從字母表中取出
You pull the letters of "Wisdom" out of the alphabet
將其放在前面
and place them at the beginning.
希伯來語的音譯放在這邊
The Hebrew transliteration goes here,
然後翻譯
and then you translate.
I變成了B
"I" becomes "B."
T變成U
"T" becomes "U."
P變成R
"P" is "R."
I和E
"I".  "E".
還有D
"D."
D
"埋葬了...以斯拉
"Buried... Ezra...
達夫"
Dove."
你知道這是什麼意思嗎
Does that mean anything to you?
不知道  聽起來像垃圾搖滾樂隊
No. Sounds like a '90s grunge band.
我知道我一直都沒有給予你和你的工作
I know I haven't always been the most supportive
最大的支持  但這次很有成效
of you and your work, but this was good.
-這是...  -科學
- It was... - Science.
就像你說的  這些詞
I mean, like you said, I had the...
一直在我腦中
words all along...
見好就收吧
Quit while you're ahead.
出人意料的是
So, big surprise,
這不是垃圾搖滾樂隊
not a grunge band.
以斯拉·達夫是共濟會會員
Ezra Dove's a Freemason.
以斯拉·達夫
以斯拉·達夫(1792-1848)是一名19世紀
居住於華盛頓特區的律師
和聲名顯赫的共濟會會員
以斯拉·達夫逝於1848年
Ezra Dove. Died 1848.
葬於橡樹山
Buried at Oaken Hill...
墓地
Cemetery.
所以尖頂石也許和他葬在一起嗎
So maybe the capstone's buried with him?
怎麼樣  你好嗎
What's up, man? How you doing?
玩得開心嗎
You having fun?
抱歉  什麼
I'm sorry, what?
也許與其...在我家門外晃悠
Maybe instead of... hanging outside my house,
你應該去找找在國會開槍的人
you should be out trying to find the guy who shot up the Capitol?
他殺了你們其中一個人
Killed one of your guys, man.
結果  你卻來這裏騷擾我
Instead, you're out here harassing me.
-我沒騷擾你  -是的  你就是
- I'm not harassing you. - Yes, you are.
你在監視我和我妻子
You're spying on me and my wife,
我這麼說讓你不舒服了
and I'm making you uncomfortable.
我也是警察  我曾爲國而戰
I'm a cop, too. Yeah, I fought for this country.
我是受害者  看看我
I'm a victim here. Look at me.
看看這個  我讓你看看這裏
Check this out. Let me show you something right here.
傷口從這裏貫穿到這裏  好嗎
It came through here and here, okay?
這個叫做"貫通傷"
Now what that's called is a through and through,
醫生給我開了藥膏
and I got cream from the doctor.
我有時手伸不到後面  這太難了
I can't get back there sometimes. It's difficult.
也許你可以幫我塗藥膏
Maybe you could help me rub it on.
或許你該回屋去  先生
Maybe you should go back inside, sir.
讓我問你個問題
Let me ask you a question.
你在這裏面怎麼上廁所
How do you go to the bathroom in here, you know?
中情局給了你個特製的瓶子嗎
CIA give you a special bottle or something?
他一直信守誓言  保持沉默
He's keeping his vow of silence.
他是彼得的好朋友
He's Peter's good friend.
如果他知道在哪裏能找到他
If he knew where to find him,
你覺得他不會告訴我們嗎
don't you think he'd tell us?
沒錯
No.
我認爲他的組織有不同的優先事項
I think that his group has different priorities.
你是說共濟會
You mean the Masons.
共濟會裏的一個組織
A group within the Masons.
利維坦社
Leviathan.
自封的智慧守衛者
Self-appointed guardians of the wisdom.
這是我們對他們的所有了解
That is everything that we know about them.
警告  絕密信息
我在國會大廈地下室見過這個符號
I saw this symbol in the Capitol basement.
彼得·所羅門之前的房間
In the room Peter Solomon had down there.
所以你在監聽他的電話
This is why you had his phone tapped.
你到底找這個入口多久了
How long have you been looking for this portal thing, exactly?
顯然  還不夠久
Not long enough, apparently.
否則我會有更多信息
Otherwise I'd have more information than that.
所以你要進去那裏
That's why you're gonna go in there
你要問出更多信息
and you're gonna get more.
利維坦社
憑藉你洞察施壓點的敏銳眼光
With your keen eye for pressure points
以及你跟所羅門家後代的關係
and your mutual connections to the Solomon offspring,
我想你不費吹灰之力就能讓他開口
I suspect that you're gonna crack him without much trouble.
所以放下後悔
So put aside regrets...
做你最擅長乾的事
and do what you do best.
我真不敢相信  這太扯了
I can't believe this. It's bullshit.
土耳其  伊斯坦布爾
四年前
我不明白  你到底要問我什麼
I don't understand what you want from me.
我一直都在這裏
I was here the entire time.
我甚至不知道艾哈邁德走了
I didn't even know Ahmad had left.
這不是我的錯
None of this is my fault.
在我來看  這恐怕並不完全正確
From where I stand, I'm afraid that's not entirely true.
當你和一位沙特王子狂歡了三天
When you go on a three-day bender with a Saudi prince
他開着法拉利撞上了電線杆
and he drives his Ferrari into a telephone pole,
當時還吸了你給的白粉
high on coke you provided,
你之前在哪裏真的不重要
it doesn't really matter where you were.
對他的家人來說絕對如此
Certainly not to his family.
你是哪裏派來的
Where are you from?
大使館嗎
The embassy?
我在那裏有間辦公室
I have an office there.
-我是來幫你的  扎克  -很好
- I'm here to help, Zach. - Good.
那你幫我聯繫我爸
Then you can help me get in touch with my dad.
他有律師  可以解決這事
He has a lawyer who can fix this.
如果他沒先殺了我的話
If he doesn't kill me first.
如果有辦法讓你不通過你父親
What if there was a way for you to take care of this
就解決此事呢
without your father?
你知道的
You know...
自己解決
...help yourself.
怎麼做
How?
去和對我們有用的人打交道
You made connections that could be useful to us.
意思是這段時間我讓你去哪就去哪
Just means going where I tell you for a bit
不要惹是生非
and keeping a clean nose.
只要這樣
Do that,
就沒有人  包括你父親
and no one... including your father,
需要知道這件事
needs to know anything about this.
我很喜歡這地方  已經到了
It's kind of gotten to the point
我不能在別的地方工作的地步
where I-I can't work anywhere else.
我有點迷信
I guess I'm a bit superstitious.
你是作家嗎
So, you're a writer?
被你發現了  是的
Guilty, yeah.
我可能知道你寫的作品嗎
Would I know anything you've written?
如果我告訴你筆名  你可能會知道
Well, if I told you my pen name, you know, possibly.
但是我纔剛認識你  所以
But I barely know you, so...
我也相信超自然事物
I believe in superstition, too.
你相信超自然事物
Oh, you believe in superstition?
說真的  我的專題論文裏
Seriously, there is a whole section
-有整整一章都在寫...  -專題論文
- in my dissertation dedicated to... - Dissertation?
-我的天啊  -哪個領域的
- Oh, my God. - In what field?
是意念科學
It's called noetic science.
我是研究助理
I'm a research assistant,
我們正在尋找靈學現象的證明
and we are looking for proof of parapsychological phenomena.
也就是身心聯結
So that's the mind-body connection,
關於靈性治療的領域
the whole spiritual healing gamut.
-沒錯  -你說真的
- Yeah. - Are you serious?
我正在寫的書就是關於靈學
The book I'm writing is all about parapsychology.
-什麼  -我向天發誓
- What? - I swear to God.
你不會正好認識凱瑟琳·所羅門吧
You-you wouldn't happen to know Katherine Solomon
不會這麼巧吧
by any chance, would you?
我認識  其實  她是我老闆
Yes, actually-- she's my boss.
-她是你老闆  -對
- She's your boss? - Yep.
真的假的
Get out of town.
其實  我剛剛還看見她了
I saw her earlier today, in fact.
-你今天看見她了  -對
- You saw her today? - Yeah.
在哪
Where?
我  我拜讀過她的很多作品
Oh, no, I... you know, I've just read a lot of her work,
-爲我最新的書做研究  -嗯
- doing research for my latest book. - Right.
她對靛藍孩童的研究
She did this study on Indigo Children.
自稱有超能力的孩子  共同特質是智力很高
直覺性強  注意力無法集中且非常敏感
真是太令人着迷了
It was really fascinating.
我協助了那份研究
I assisted that study.
不會吧
No way.
我能請你再喝一杯咖啡嗎
Could I buy you another cup of coffee?
-如果你有時間的話  -可以
- I mean, if you have time, of course. - Sure.
不如還是喝酒吧
How about a glass of wine instead?
-好啊  可以的  -好
- I'd love that. Yeah, sure. - Okay.
天吶
Oh, my...
我到底做了什麼
I cannot believe I just did that.
我很抱歉
I'm... I am so sorry.
沒事  我去快速地收拾一下
Oh, it's nothing. I'll just... I'm gonna go clean up quick.
-我馬上回來  -不用說
- I'll be right back. - Needless to say,
-這杯酒我請  -好  成交
- the wine's on me. - Okay. Deal.
輸入密碼
我是凱絲  情況緊急
剛給你打了電話
看到短信回撥這個電話
我們得找個地圖
We're gonna need to find a map.
這個地方很大  他有可能被埋在任何地方
This place is huge. He could be buried anywhere.
不好意思
Excuse me.
需要幫忙嗎
Can I help you?
是的  我們在找人
Yes. We're looking for someone.
一個...死人
Someone... dead.
顯而易見
Obviously.
我們的祖父
Our grandfather.
我們大老遠從馬布爾黑德開車來探望他
We drove all the way from Marblehead to see him.
對吧  肖恩
Right, Sean?
對  我  肖恩  和我的好...
Yes. I, Sean, and, uh, my wonderful...
妹妹
Sister.
我妹妹和我很想向祖父表達
...sister and I w-would love to pay our respects
我們的敬意
to, um, Grandpa.
對他來說談論這個還是很艱難
It's still hard for him to talk about it.
痛苦永遠不會離開
Pain never leaves a person.
所以我們建造了紀念堂
It's why we build monuments to it.
如果我們沒這麼做  這裏就是高爾夫球場了
If we didn't, you'd be standing on a golf course.
是的
Right.
你們可以在左邊的小路
You'll find the directory to the grounds
找到各區域的名址錄
off the path to the left.
-謝謝  謝謝  神父  -謝謝
- Thank you. Thanks, Father. - Thanks.
以斯拉·達夫
以斯拉·達夫  Y09
他在這  但等等
There he is. But hold on.
-什麼  -密碼說的是"埋葬了"
- What? - Uh, the code said "Buried."
這顯示他在Y09區  是骨灰安置所
This says he's in section Y09, which is the columbarium.
所以他沒有被埋葬嗎
So he's not buried at all?
沒有
No.
以斯拉·達夫
鴿子飛了
你要拿它做什麼
What are you gonna do with that?
我會按下那個按鈕
I'm gonna push that button.
然後你把我想知道的都告訴我
Then you're gonna tell me what I want to know.
你的上司不喜歡弄髒他的手嗎
Your boss doesn't like getting his hands dirty?
所以他把這事交給了你
So he leaves that to you?
本質上  是的
Essentially, yeah.
但他和我並不總是意見一致
But he and I don't always see eye to eye.
這是A80短程電磁脈衝發射器
This is an A80 short-range EMP generator.
我剛剛讓攝像頭短路了
I just shorted out the cameras.
很快他們就會帶來新的
Pretty soon they'll bring new ones,
但在那發生之前的一切完全是我們之間的事
but whatever happens before then is completely between us.
我不在乎能不能找到入口
Look, I don't care about finding some portal.
我只是想找到你的朋友彼得·所羅門
I just want to find your friend Peter Solomon.
中情局一般不會參與失蹤人口的調查
CIA doesn't generally involve itself in missing persons.
我有自己的原因
I have a personal interest.
他兒子扎克里曾是我們的線人
His son Zachary was one of our assets.
我知道是因爲我招募了他
I know because I recruited him.
這是我第一次和這麼年輕的人一起工作
It was the first time I'd worked with someone so young.
還英年早逝
And lost.
我以爲他能應付得來
I thought he could handle it.
當他因爲販毒被關進監獄時
When he was thrown into prison for trafficking,
我接到命令  要否認與他有任何瓜葛
I was ordered to disavow any knowledge of him.
放棄他
To burn him.
所以我照做了
So that's what I did.
那又怎樣
So what?
你覺得找到彼得就會讓一切都好起來嗎
You think finding Peter will make everything all right?
不會
No.
但這將是一個開始
But it'd be a start.
我們快沒時間了
We're running out of time.
我對抓走他的人一無所知
Look, I don't know anything about the man who took him.
你知道他在找什麼
You know what he's after.
如果我知道那是什麼  我就能理解他
If I understand that, I can understand him,
這可能決定了彼得的生或死
and that might be the difference between Peter living and dying.
Y區
Section Y.
以斯拉·達夫
1792-1848
他在那
There he is.
確保沒人進來
Make sure no one comes in.
-你要幹什麼  -別擔心  我能搞定
- What are you doing? - Don't worry, I got it.
窄的地方另說  但我不怕高
Tight spaces are one thing; heights I can handle.
爲什麼會有人
Why would somebody hide
把尖頂石藏在骨灰缸裏
a capstone in an urn anyway?
許多文化對褻瀆人類遺體有迷信說法
Many cultures have superstitions about desecrating human remains.
當然  我一點也不信  但有種強力的威懾...
I don't believe in of them, of course. But a strong deter...
接得好
Nice catch.
救了我們
Saved us.
而你想讓我覺得你不迷信嗎
And you want me to believe you're not superstitious?
我只是在擔心干擾因素
I was worried about the noise.
好吧...
Well...
證明一下
prove it.
我們有麻煩了
We got a problem.
這裏面除了骨灰  什麼都沒有
There's nothing in here but ash.
什麼
What?
這還不僅是我們唯一的麻煩
That's not our only problem.
有人知道我們在這裏了
Someone knows we're here.
-誰  -不重要  我們得走了
- Who? - Doesn't matter. We have to go.
如果有人想要阻止我們
If someone's trying to stop us,
意味着我們找對了地方
that means we're on the right track.
尖頂石肯定在這裏的某個地方
The capstone must be here somewhere.
-你在幹什麼  -爭取時間
- What are you doing? - Buying time.
天吶
Oh, my God.
-再次抱歉  我...  -天吶  沒事
- Apologies again. I'm... - Oh, my God. It's all good.
-謝謝你的酒  -當然
- Thank you for the wine. - Of course.
敬身心聯結
To the mind-body connection.
-乾杯  -乾杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
好吧  我有件事要坦白
Well, I have a confession to make.
我坐下時  就知道你的身份
I knew exactly who you were when I sat down.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你的手指...
Your finger...
你現在該離開了
You should probably go now.
慢點
Easy.
我們肯定沒注意到什麼東西
There's got to be something we're not seeing.
好的  埋葬  沒被埋
Okay, um, buried, not buried.
14個字母  智慧  列王  心
14 letters. Wisdom. Kings. Heart.
他馬上到了  而你還把我們鎖住了
He's almost here, and you locked us in!
是啊  是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊
Yeah.
《聖經》中希伯來的預言者
曾在鯨魚的肚子裏度過三天三夜
約拿
Jonah.
蘭登
Langdon.
埋葬的鴿子
Buried Dove.
蘭登
Langdon.
在希伯來語裏  約拿是鴿子的意思
In Hebrew, Jonah means "Dove."
蘭登
Langdon!
快點
Come on!
這些浮雕講述了約拿和鯨魚的故事
These reliefs tell the story of Jonah and the Whale.
-趴下  -而鯨魚用希伯來語怎麼說
- Get down! - And what's another word for "Whale"?
利維坦
Leviathan.
看
Look.
這裏面有東西
There's something in here.
天吶
Oh, my God.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait.
在這裏
It's here.
-這不是尖頂石  -趕緊拿上走人
- It's not the capstone. - Just take it and keep going.
這裏
Here.
不
No!
約拿是如何逃脫的
How did Jonah get out again?
上帝發令了
God commanded it.
現在就是好時機
Well, now would be a good time.
蘭斯
Hey, hey, Lace.
最近如何  兄弟
What's up, man?
是的  我知道  抱歉  現在很晚了
Yeah, I know. I'm sorry. It's late.
嗯  沒事
Yeah, yeah, no, all good.
我今天出院了
Yeah, I got out today.
聽着
So, listen, um...
你們發現了關於槍手的任何信息嗎
you, uh, you got anything on the shooter?
我知道  中情局說是什麼"絕密"信息
Yeah, yeah, I know, the CIA got some "Eyes only" Bullshit,
但我們的監控拍到了他  對嗎
but... we got him on camera, right?
在克里爾維尤系統裏搜一下  給我個名字
So run him through Clearview, get me a name.
嗯  明天可以
Yeah, tomorrow works fine.
謝了  我欠你個人情
Thanks, man. I owe you one.
好的
All right, man,
你繼續看保齡球什麼的吧
go back to watching bowling or whatever.
好
All right.
附近的所有單位
...all units in vicinity,
代碼1號  亞當斯紀念醫院
Code 1, Adams Memorial.
無反應女性  身份未知
Nonresponsive female, yet to be identified.
現場發現黑紅色廂式旅行車
Black and red SUV found at scene.
馬里蘭州牌照
Maryland license plate number...
彼得
Peter...
把我召進了利維坦社
brought me into the Leviathan Group.
是他揭示了它的目的
He was the one who revealed its purpose.
所有共濟會都會講述關於深藏祕密的故事
All Masons tell stories about deeply held secrets.
大多數是爲了激起新成員興趣的怪談
Most of them are tall tales to intrigue new members.
但這個不一樣
But this was different.
史密森尼博物館所有
我在這些人身上看到了
I saw in these men
一種信仰
a belief...
信仰超越可能的事物
in something beyond possibility.
信仰
A belief
古老的智慧不僅真實存在
that the ancient wisdom was not only real,
而且還能解除意識
but that it could unlock consciousness,
讓人能進入
allowing man to access
隱藏的權力寶庫
hidden reservoirs of power.
這個組織建立在
The group was formed
兩個問題的基礎上
based on two questions:
人類能否應對這樣的演變
Could humanity handle such an evolution?
如果這個權力
And what might happen
落入壞人手中會發生什麼
if this power fell into the wrong hands?
我們協定
We made a pact
要保衛那些線索
to safeguard the clues.
但是神話的誘惑力很強
But the lure of the myth was strong.
傳言
There's a story
上個世紀初
of a member of the group
該組織有一個成員
from the beginning of the last century
對他來說  誘惑太大
for whom the lure was too great.
他拋棄了他的誓言
He abandoned his oath.
他爲自己尋求智慧
He sought the wisdom for himself.
他也找到了
And he found it.
據說他學會了控制事物
It is said that he learned to control things,
他可以使物質屈服於他的意志
that he could bend matter to his will.
天吶
Oh, God.
我09年在法蘭克福用過脈衝發射器這招
I did an EMP gambit in Frankfurt in '09.
當時可沒有這些
I didn't have one of these.
我就用車庫搖控器
I'd use a garage door opener.
你想怎麼處置他
What do you want to do with him?
放了他
Cut him loose.
現在你獲得了他的信任  可以根據需要利用他
Now that you've bonded, you can use him as needed.
是他嗎
Is it him?
指幾部存在於希臘文七十士譯本
但不存在於希伯來文聖經的著作
是一句出自《次經》的引述
It's a quote from the Apocrypha.
《馬加比家族》的第四本書
Fourth Book of the Maccabees.
"你若因你的不順服
"For if you dispose me to anger
而使我發怒
"By your disobedience...
你將迫使我用可怕的刑罰
"You will compel me, with dreadful punishments...
來毀滅
"...to destroy
你們所有人"
every one of you."